# **David Silvera**

**Data Scientist** 

ingenieria.d.s.g@hotmail.com • +542657626313

https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidsilveragabriel/ • https://github.com/DavidSilveraGabriel

## **Summary**

Self-taught Data Scientist with +2 years of experience, worked as a freelancer in the areas of neuroscience, developing an end-to-end EEG classifier for move an arduino robot with the mind in just 3 month, also computer vision, creating an app that controls the mouse estimating the pose of the head and eyes, and today in education as a tutor of data science

### **Skills**

Python • Machine learning • Data Science • Numpy • Pandas • Matplotlib • SQL • Computer vision

## **Work Experience**

Data Scientist Tutor

Nov 2021 – present

CoderHouse • Freelance

Remote

### Technologies: Python • Machine learning • Pandas • Numpy • Data Science

In charge of monitoring +50 students, correcting challenges, deliverables and final projects, too i'm responsible for teaching complementary classes with reviews of 4.9/5

#### **Data Scientist Freelance**

Jul 2020 - Oct 2021 • 1 yr 3 mos

Fiverr • Freelance

Remote

### Technologies: Python • Machine learning • Data Science • Numpy • Matplotlib

Freelance Data Scientist, work on fiverr platform with 9 successfully completed jobs as data scientist, fully satisfied customers, \*\*\*\*\* rating. my profile: https://www.fiverr.com/davidsilverag

## **Projects**

**EEG classifier** Apr 2020 – Jul 2020 • 3 mos

## Technologies: Python • Numpy • Mne • Braindecode • Artificial intelligence

In this mini project i use the libraries mne and braindecode to analyze and classify public domain EEG(ML) signals provided by physionet.org here the paper from braindecode where is studied deep ConvNets with a range of different architectures, designed for decoding imagined or executed movements from raw EEG

### **Computer Pointer Controller**

Apr 2020 - Jun 2020 • 2 mos

## Technologies: Python • Opencv • Numpy • Computer vision

Computer Pointer Controller app estimate pose of head and is used to controll the movement of mouse pointer by the direction of eyes. This app takes video as input and then app estimates eye-direction and head-pose and based on that estimation it move the mouse pointer.

### **Educations**

## Nanodegree: Artificial Intelligence

Mar 2020 - Jul 2020 • 4 mos

Udacity

I've worked in the development of cutting-edge Edge AI applications for the future of the Internet of Things. I've Used the Intel® Distribution of OpenVINO™ Toolkit to fast-track development of high-performance computer vision & deep learning inference applications.

Course: Programming May 2017 - Jan 2018 • 8 mos

Plan 111 Mil

Villa Mercedes, Argentina

Trained to develop and interpret UML, with a solid foundation in Java programming and knowledge advanced in the query language par excellence SQL

# Languages

**Spanish** (Native or bilingual proficiency)

English (Full professional proficiency)